That such a news which is ready to rate the entire sector,
our correspondent Anurag
Shaharma is present in the Sat program and the
register was also being mentioned, regarding the same,
big action is being prepared for the insurance companies,
tell me the translation, is all this equal, the way the
focus will be on the insurance sector in the budget
and a big announcement is going to be made, the
2FA limit related to the insurance sector can be
increased from 49 percent to 74 percent
and according to our source,
both from the note of the Finance Ministry and from the decree side, we are
confirming it in a small way that
in this budget, a lot of emphasis is being given on increasing the FDI limit
and it can be
announced and there is also logic behind it
because the way the insurance sector is
developing in India and there are
possibilities in the insurance sector in the future
and the existing companies
need capital, so keeping this in mind, the government can announce increasing the FDI
in the insurance sector from 39 to 1950 percent topper point, in the
pre-budget meeting that has been held in the recent days  There
too, all the insurance companies, there are
two bodies of General Insurance Council related to insurance, it was
also requested by them
that for
further growth of the insurance sector, there is a need to promote it,
all the things have been passed in this, which our sources
related to the Finance Ministry are telling that there is a
problem in the ownership regulation, so the
government can make a change in it
that even after increasing the FDI to 74 percent, the
ownership and management control will remain with the
Indian companies, which will be
domestic companies, so
work is being done on this and it is expected
that after making a consensus on this, it will be announced in the budget
that the limit of ownership and management control in insurance will be
increased from 59% to 10%, that the scale of
ownership and management control is
eligible for domestic companies,
I Anil, this will be big news
for the sector, Sir, if the limit of insurance coverage is
increased then you will be completely concerned,
Secretary, and the biggest thing is that there will be a
headline of the budget on that day, if we talk about it then the
alarm will be raised.
Before I analyze this, I would like to ask Anurag one more thing:
tell me why you
are so confident that this time in the budget, it is
possible that the government's preparations can be
completed to the level of appointments,
hence there is a lot of confidence. People
associated with the insurance industry are
confirming this and saying
that this time the budget may increase. Secondly, people
associated with the Finance Ministry are
also saying that this time the budget will increase. The
qualities
are big. If sources related to the regulator and the ministry are
saying that this time there may be an increase in the budget,
and this
increase has been going on for the last few years, a
lot of emphasis was given in the last budget also.
Apart from this, many domestic
companies, insurance companies, which are
domestic promoters, want to unite.
Even after 15 years, after this year they
created and took their car companies forward, so
they also want to unlock the value.
Apart from this, there are some companies which have
kept the limit at 59% and
foreign investors want to come there, but due to the
limit of 59%, foreign
investors are not able to come.  If they are not able to come, then due to all these reasons, there is a
belief that this time there may be an
increase in the failure and apart from that, if
you look at it in a holistic view, the
research report of Reserve Bank of India
says that as per their survey, the
insurance sector is the only sector where public
spending is big, this is what the Reserve Bank
report says, so as per the possibility, the
GDP penetration in India as compared to just two yards is up
to three percent and the global penetration is
seven and a half percent, so if foreign companies come, they will bring
their own technology
and these foreign companies also know
how big is the score in insurance in India because it is a completely
penetrated market.